# Arthur Zherka

📍 Warsaw, PL 📞 (48) 792-586-234 📮

arthurzherko@gmail.com

I do frontends. Got a bit of experience with React and Next.js and Node.js, mere couple decades give or take. A few other things here and there too, like development of PWA, backend architecture, managing small company in Warsaw. Most of my professional experience was with startup projects and small to medium size teams, long-term more often than short term. I could be frontend lead in your new startup company if you manage to get me inspired by your idea and people are nice but strongly prefer flat team structure, leading with experience and example, and being agile rather than doing agile. A result-oriented professional, following best practices to produce optimal solutions, great team player. Big corporate super-structured anything... well, contact me and we'll have to see.

### **Technologies**

- JavaScript, TypeScript
- React, React Native, Redux Thunk, Redux Saga, Webpack
- Node.js, Express, GraphQL

- MongoDB, Redis
- AWS, Firebase

#### **Experience**

# **Senior Frontend Developer**

Suno, Inc

Sep 2022 - Apr 2023

Software for the Savvy Audiologist

- Developed the website for audiology clinics across USA that allows you to make an appointment with doctors via the built-in event calendar (Typescript, React, Redux Toolkit, React Scheduler)
- Implemented SOAP note creation and editing with voice input, automatic creation of pdf reports (Lexical, microphone-stream, jsPDF)
- Developed a chat with infinite scrolling (WebSocket API)
- Developed interactive graphs, forms with draggable elements (chart.js, react-draggable, react-dnd)
- Developed a large number of components (100+) in a tight schedule
- Test coverage of each component and each feature (Cypress)

# **Frontend Developer**

#### **Lesido (contract with CodeControl)**

June 2021 - Today

app.lesido.de - The digital picture book library with interactive video chat

The React Native application can be found on the German App Store by searching for "Lesido"

- Developed the website and React Native application for interactive book reading using modern technologies (React, Typescript, Hooks, SWR, Recoil)
- Implemented audio and video capabilities for the web and mobile application. (The Amazon Chime SDK)
- Implemented synchronisation of cursor, book pages, routing during a call between users (WebSocket API)
- Implemented a subscription system with a trial periods and discount coupons (Stripe)
- Developed Book Reader with lazy loading pages (react-pdf, react-window)
- Implemented a notification system using Firebase Cloud Messaging (FCM)
- Implemented analytics tools for capturing user events (PostHog, GTM)

# **Full-stack Developer**

Fractal

Sep 2020 – October 2021

Fractal - Accounting software

- Developed backend that interacted with the API of two trading platforms (EXANTE and BitMEX ) finding suitable options for buying and selling instruments (GraphQL, Express)
- Led a small team (3 people) in the development of a web application to interact with the backend (React, GraphQL)
- Developed comparison table to show the best options for buying and selling instruments

# **Full-stack Developer**

**Sportrecs (contract)** 

Mar 2020 - Sep 2020

Sportrecs.com - Sports Broadcasting Services

- Developed backend (GraphQL, Express, Razzle)
- Implemented a broadcast monitoring system (FPS, bandwidth, speed) with interactive level-of-detail rendering of large graphs (React, Chart.js)
- Developed the mechanism of creating and validation of widgets for partner sites (React)

# **Frontend Developer**

Maxiru (contract)

Oct 2016 - Feb 2020

Virgin Voyages - Application to play media in cabin

- Rewrote the old frontend with a new, faster one using modern best practices and recent technologies (React, React Native)
- Implemented WebSockets in application for real-time dashboard updates
- Reduced project build time (more than 15 seconds) by reconfiguring Webpack
- Coordinated releases and the implementation of features
- Covered 80% of code with unit tests

Virgin Voyages - Application for online check-in, booking and just about everything smooth sailing

- Developed the application with a user-friendly UI (React Native, Redux Thunk, Webpack)
- Developed variety (50+) of responsive components
- Implemented biometric authentication, PIN code, document detection and photo editor
- Integrated wearable tech accessories (bracelets) via Bluetooth
- Developed CI/CD process for infrastructure (Jenkins)
- Developed animations (react-spring)

Maxiru - Map Editor project (web editor for vector graphics)

- Developed a web application for pathfinding and navigation on SVG map
- Developed UI components based on trigonometric formulas
- Achieved 80% code coverage for unit tests using Jest

Maxiru - Web simulator of an Unreal Engine 4 application

- Developed a real-time web app to display the simulated movement of the bots from Unreal Engine 4
- Designed and developed the core architecture of SPA based on client requirements (React, Redux Thunk, Immutable.js)
- Developed a web dashboard with editable spreadsheets and auto save

DeepVideo - Service for video that helps viewers to identify products

- Developed SPA (Angular 2 and D3.js) with responsive UI and interactive graphs (zoomable bar chart)
- Developed with Angular 2 editable spreadsheets with auto save, sorting, filters and search with autocomplete

Woo Club - Shoppable video platform project

- Developed a new variety (20+) of responsive, accessible and localizable UI components with Vue.js
- Integrated a 3rd party YouTube API with for the ability to add tags to on videos to display the products that appear in them

Web Developer Freelance Jun 2015 – Sep 2016

- Developed 8 responsive landing pages (HTML, CSS, Javascript, Gulp)
- Cleaned up variety (10+) of hacked Wordpress sites (malware, spam, access recovery)

#### **Education**

Bachelor's degree in Business Economics and Management, Polessky State University

Sep 2013 - Jul 2017